3.
スリー
ワン
(管制官)３！２！１！
リフトオフ！
2.
1.
Liftoff.
It's blinding...
なんば　むった
(南波六太)まっぶし～！
ワシの名は デニール･ヤング｡
My name is Deneil Young.
ナサ
ＮＡＳＡ主任教官パイロット…｡
NASA chief pilot instructor?
パイロット～!?
Pilot?!
そうじゅう
ヒビトにジェット機の操縦を
叩き込んだのはワシだ！
I'm the one who taught Hibito how to fly a jet.
え…マ マジかよ…｡
Eh?
S-Seriously?
自分の弟が宇宙に行くってのは
どんな気分だ？お？
How does it feel to watch your little brother go into space?
くも
最初は やたら曇ってて そのうち
ちゅうとはんぱ
中途半端な感じになって➡
It started off cloudy.
Then it cleared up a little...
今は…晴れてる｡
And now, it's sunny.
(ﾃﾞﾆｰﾙ)まあ 人生もそうだ｡
空模様と同じだ｡
Well, life is like the weather.
It can be sunny or cloudy.
ところでムッタ ｢空｣と｢人生｣の➡
By the way, Mutta...
Do you know the biggest difference between life and the sky?
一番の違いは
何だか知ってるか？お？
｢空｣は誰のもんでもない｡
｢人生｣は自分のもんだ｡
The sky doesn't belong to anyone.
Your life belongs to you.
人生はコントロールが効く｡
You can control your own life.
Seven Days
Space Brothers
Before my uneasiness
was the end
of my happiness
I came to you
and we were one
Hello Hello
Let's fly
Here in this world we dream
and keep on dancing
Here among light and shadow
we keep changing
so that the wind doesn't let up
Even though the future is vague and unreliable
we are
not alone
#32 A Private Place
Lobster!
(南波母)エビ！エビ！➡
エビよ お父さん！エビ エビ！
エビ エビ！
There's lobster, dear.
Lobster, lobster...
Lobster, lobster!
うどんは英語で何て言うんだ？
How do you say udon in English?
うどんなんて ないわよ
お父さん｡エビよ｡
They don't serve udon here, dear.
Order lobster.
なすだ
(茄子田)え～ それでは皆さま｡
Okay...
Well, everyone.
Let's drink to Hibito's successful launch.
ひびと
日々人君のね 打ち上げ成功を
祝しまして…➡
かんぱい
乾杯といきましょうね！
せ～の！
Bottoms up.
Ready and...
(一同)カンパーイ！
Cheers!
(ケンジ)よかったな ムッ君｡
I'm happy for you, Mu.
Yeah.
(せりか)おめでとうございます｡
Congratulations.
ありがとう せりかさん｡
Thanks, Serika...
まあ～大きなロブスター｡
That's one big lobster!
茄子田理事長も
かんがい
感慨深いんだろうな｡
Director Nasuda has a lot to think about.
え なに!?
いや…｡
Huh? What?
Well...
《日本に帰ったら
忙しくなるね～｡➡
I'll be busy once I get back to Japan.
日々人君関連のテレビの特番に
新聞･雑誌･ネットにラジオ｡➡
There will be TV appearances related to Hibito, as well as newspaper, magazine, Internet, and radio events.
アニメになるかもね｡
新しいネクタイ買っとこうね》
They might even make an anime.
I should buy a new tie...
《茄子田さん…》
Nasuda...
Now, for those candidates here,
つるみ
(鶴見)さて 受験生の皆さん
今後の日程を説明します｡
I will explain the next step.
まず 今夜の便で皆さんは
日本に帰り➡
You will all be flying back to Japan tonight,
それぞれ職場に戻ってください｡➡
so please return to your regular jobs.
ごうひ
合否の結果発表は 日々人君が
月面に着陸してから１週間後➡
One week after Hibito lands on the moon, the results will be announced.
３月１５日の１２時頃を
予定しています｡
We expect it will happen at around noon, on March 15th.
ジャクサ
我々 ＪＡＸＡ職員が
皆さんの自宅に➡
You will receive a call from JAXA at your residences, so please be ready.
直接 電話をかけるので
たいき
待機しておいてください｡
お楽しみに！
Sit tight.
＜その夜 みんなは日本に帰り➡
Afterward, everyone left,
私は１人 ヒューストンに残った｡
日々人の月面着陸の瞬間を➡
while I stayed in Houston.
I chose to remain there to watch Hibito land on the moon.
ヒューストンで
見守ることにした＞
[TV]♪～
Nagata Benjamin
[TV](永田)こんばんは｡
ニュース６時でホイ｡➡
Good evening.
This is the 6:00 news.
I'm Nagata Benjamin.
司会の永田ベンジャミンです｡➡
今日の特集は
｢芸能人が経営する人気店｣｡➡
Tonight, we have a story on a celebrity restaurant.
Bomber Miura's                           Restaurant!!
Popular
The Korean barbecue restaurant opened by former pro wrestler Bomber Miura is a big hit.
元プロレスラーの
ボンバー三浦さんが開いた➡
焼肉店が大繁盛｡
その人気の裏側に迫ります｡
Bomber
Let's see why that is.
[TV](ﾎﾞﾝﾊﾞｰ)んめぇよぉ～！
Bomber
It's good.
[TV](永田)
そして６時半からは
日本人初の月面着陸を控えた➡
And at 6:30, we have Nanba Hibito, the astronaut poised to become the first Japanese person on the moon.
あの南波日々人宇宙飛行士が
登場！➡
現在 月へ向かっている
宇宙船オリオンから生中継で➡
We'll have a live interview with Nanba Hibito as he travels to the moon aboard the spacecraft Orion.
月までの旅の様子を
伝えてもらいます｡➡
お見逃しなく｡
You won't want to miss it.
[TV](南波日々人)
ちょっと 角度変えた方が
いいかも｡
I should probably adjust the angle.
[TV](ﾌﾚﾃﾞｨ)
もう始まってるぞ ヒビト｡
[TV]えっ マジ？
Camera's rolling, Hibito.
Huh? Seriously?
Don't touch the mic.
[TV](ﾌﾚﾃﾞｨ)マイクのとこ触るなって｡
[TV](咳払い)
[TV]日本の皆さん こんばんは～｡➡
Good evening, everyone in Japan.
宇宙飛行士の南波日々人です｡
あ～っ！日々人よ｡
I'm astronaut Nanba Hibito.
It's Hibito, dear! It's Hibito!
お父さん 日々人！
息子よ ホラホラッ！
Look, it's our son!
息子だな｡
[TV]日本は今…｡
It's our son.
In Japan, it's around 6:30 PM, right?
夜の６時３０分ですね｡
よく｢宇宙は何時ですか｣という
質問があるんですが➡
A lot of people like to ask what time it is in space.
僕達 宇宙飛行士には
２つの時刻表示があります｡
Astronauts follow two different clocks.
エムイーティー
１つはＭＥＴというやつで これは
ロケットが発射された時から➡
The first one is MET, Mission Elapsed Time, which starts as soon as the rocket is launched.
カウントがスタートする
ミッション経過時間です｡
[TV]今は６７時間３０分です｡➡
Currently, it's 67:30.
The other 24-hour clock on this spacecraft
もう１つは この宇宙船の
２４時間表示で…｡
ヒューストンと同じ時刻に
合わせてあります｡
is set to use Houston time.
ただ月面は 国際的に利用する
場所なので…｡
But since the moon is an international zone,
月に着いたら イギリスの
グリニッジ標準時刻に➡
we'll be switching to Greenwich Mean Time upon arrival.
パッと切り替えます｡
Here's a shot of the male crew members.
(ﾊﾞﾃﾞｨ)ハーイ！
コンニチワ！
え～今 ご覧の映像は➡
Hi.
Konnichiwa.
当クルーの男性メンバーです｡
僕らは明後日
日本時間で早朝５時頃…｡
In two days, around 5 AM, in Japan...
見えますか？
Can you see it?
(原田)わあ…近づいてる！
They're getting close.
いいね いいね～｡
Absolutely splendid.
[TV]では ここで改めて
一緒に月に向かっている…｡
≪あれ？≫
Next, I'd like to introduce the crew members who are heading to the moon.
Huh?
[TV]クルーを紹介したいと思います｡
あんな若いのだっけ
月行く人って｡
Was the astronaut going to the moon supposed to be this young?
Currently, Karen Jones and Linda Cliff are on their sleep shift.
もうちょっと
オジサンじゃなかったか？
I thought he was older.
あずま
≪お前 それ 吾妻さんと
間違ってるよ≫
You're probably thinking of Azuma.
So right now, it's pure testosterone in here.
Yeah, that's it... Azuma!
≪ああ そうだ 吾妻！
吾妻は どこ行ったんだ？≫
I'll just go around the room.
What happened to Azuma?
Beats me.
≪さあ？≫
[TV]最初の１人｡
First up is...
この人はダミアン･クウェラー｡
Damian Kweller.
僕らが｢クイーン｣と呼んでいる
着陸船アルタイルの➡
He handles the system checks for the landing craft Altair, which we call Queen.
システムチェックをしています｡
いい笑顔してます｡
He has a nice smile.
交代制の為 本来なら今
寝ているはずの➡
Our captain, Freddy Saturn, is supposed to be asleep since it's his turn, but he's running through a checklist.
船長 フレディ･サターンは
チェックリストを確認中｡
映りたくて起きてきました｡
He got up so he could be on camera.
そして もう１人は
バディ･ウォーターズ｡
And last, we have Buddy Waters.
わざわざシャツを脱いで
筋トレをしています｡
He took off his shirt to do some strength training.
日本のみんなに
筋肉を見せたいそうです｡
He wants everyone in Japan to see his muscles.
あれ？僕 終わり？
Wait? That's it for me?
とまあ こんな感じで 僕らは
月へと向かっているワケですが…｡
And so, we're continuing to make our way to the moon.
最後に反対側の窓から
みなさんにプレゼントを…｡
Finally, I have a present for everyone courtesy of the rear window.
僕らの故郷➡
Our home...
ピンポン球サイズになった
地球です｡
A ping pong ball-sized Earth.
(母)お父さん
家は どの辺かしらねえ？
Dear, where's our house?
(父)裏側だろ…今 夜だから…｡
The other side.
Because it's night.
それでは皆さん
次回は月面からお届けします｡
Well, our next transmission will be from the moon.
(ｼﾞｪﾆﾌｧｰ)ぐる～っとね｡➡
Like this...
こんな感じで ゆっくり
回転させながら進むのよ｡
It slowly spins as it travels.
フレディ達のオリオンも そう｡
Orion, which carries Freddy's team, behaves the same way.
なぜ回すか わかる人いる？➡
Does anyone know why it spins?
まあ いないわよね｡
Of course not.
はいはい わかるわかる｡
Oh, oh! I know.
あんたに聞いてないわよ｡フウ…｡
I wasn't asking you.
要するに あれだよ｡
こ～う回転してないとね➡
So basically, it has to keep spinning...
船体の片面に ずっと太陽が
当たりっぱなしになって➡
Otherwise, the same side would always be exposed to the sun,
陰の面との温度差が
大きくなるだろ｡➡
making it significantly hotter than the other side.
That might lead to complications, which could result in an accident.
そうなると 船体に悪影響が出て
事故の原因になるから回すんだよ｡
要するに
ローストチキンと一緒だ｡
It's just like roasting a chicken.
なっ わかったな キッズ達｡
なるほど～！
へえ！
Well?
Understand now, kids?
That makes sense.
《フッフッ｡見たか ジェニファー
俺の方が教えるのがウマイ》
See that, Jennifer?
I'm a better teacher.
ありがとう おばちゃん｡
(ｼﾞｪﾆﾌｧｰ)先生と呼びなさい！
Thanks, lady.
That should be, "Thanks, ma'am."
あんたも帰りなさいよ｡
人の仕事の邪魔ばっかしてないで｡
You should be leaving...
Instead of interfering with my work.
だって ここからしか
見えねえじゃん｡
But I have to stay here.
管制の様子とか
日々人達の様子が…｡
If I want to see how the mission is going,
how Hibito and the crew are doing.
中 入れてくんねえかなぁ？
ダメに決まってんでしょ｡➡
Think they'd let me in?
Of course not.
兄弟だからって 入れるわけには
いかない場所なのよ｡
They won't let you in that place because you're his brother.
(ｼﾞｪﾆﾌｧｰ)ムッタ 外 見てみ｡
Mutta, look outside.
Hmm?
アズマファミリーよ｡
たまに来るの｡
It's the Azuma family.
They come here from time to time.
へぇ～ 子供が２人いたのか｡
Oh, he has two kids.
あの奥さんは テレビで
見たことあるなぁ｡
I've seen his wife on TV before.
《美人だから覚えてる》
I remember because she's pretty.
(ｼﾞｪﾆﾌｧｰ)アズマは今
相当悔しいでしょうね｡➡
Azuma must be upset.
ヒビトに先に行かれて｡
Since Hibito beat him to the moon.
《そうなのか？やっぱり…》
Is that really true?
笑ってる…｡
He's smiling.
(ｼﾞｪﾆﾌｧｰ)アズマが笑うのは
家族といる時だけよ｡➡
Azuma only smiles when he's with his family.
だから 誰もあの中には入らないわ
貴重な時間でしょうからね｡
That's why everyone stays away.
He values his personal time with his family.
ちょっと あんた！
H-Hold on!
知らないわよ～｡
Out of my hands...
吾妻さん…こんにちは｡
Azuma.
Hello.
Congratulations on a successful launch.
(吾妻)打ち上げ成功 おめでとう｡
あ…ありがとうございます！
Th-Thank you very much.
Excuse me...
かよこ
(香代子)あの～南波六太さんです
よね？私 知ってます！
Are you Nanba Mutta?
I recognize you.
テレビで見ました｡
Huh?
I saw you on TV.
(香代子)あの～…何だっけ？
消火器男 ですか？
Um... What was it...
The fire extinguisher man... Maybe?
Yes, that was it!
(香代子)そう それです！
Have a seat.
(吾妻)まあ 座れよ｡
あ～…はい｡
Oh, thank you.
あれ？➡
Huh?
意外と なごやか…｡
It looks peaceful.
Uh...
あの 今 何となく
思ったんですが…｡
I just now realized something.
もしかして 日々人に
ゆず
先を譲ってくれたんですか？
Did you let Hibito go first?
Houston, all crew members are wearing pressure suits.
(通信:ﾌﾚﾃﾞｨ)ヒューストン｡全員
よあつふく
与圧服に着替えた｡➡
これから 着陸船に移って
待機する｡
We will begin moving to the landing craft.
(ｽﾋﾟｰｶｰ:管制)了解｡
さあ いよいよ着陸だぞ みんな｡
Roger that.
Okay, it's time to land, everyone.
(カレン)ドキドキしてきた｡
Yeah.
I'm getting excited.
It's amazing...
《すっげえなぁ》
もしかして 日々人に
先を譲ってくれたんですか？
Did you let Hibito go first?
(吾妻)何故 そう思う？
いや…何となく｡
What makes you think that?
Well, I just had a feeling.
Azuma is nothing like they say.
《吾妻さんは 噂とは違う人だ》
別に譲ったわけじゃない
上官の決断だ｡
I didn't let him go first.
It was a decision made higher up.
Congratulations on a successful launch.
⦅打ち上げ成功 おめでとう⦆
In that instant,
《あの瞬間 日々人が吾妻さんを
尊敬してしまう理由が➡
I realized why Hibito respects Azuma.
わかった気がした｡
この人のことを➡
I'd guess there aren't too many people who truly understand him.
本当に理解している人間は
少ないんじゃないだろうか》
(悌次郎)ねえねえ お兄ちゃん！
あそぼ！
Hey, mister...
Let's play.
(悌次郎)ほら 野球のと
サッカーもあるよ！
Look.
I have a baseball and a soccer ball.
お いいねえ｡やろう！
Oh, nice.
Let's play.
I prefer soccer.
お兄ちゃんは
サッカーが好きだな｡
じゃあ お兄ちゃんは地球ね！
Then you get to be Earth.
地球？
Earth?
僕は 月！
I'm the moon.
このくらい遠いんだよ 月って！
The moon is this far away!
サッカーやんないの？
Aren't we playing soccer?
お兄ちゃん 地球を
自転させて 自転！
Mister, make the earth rotate.
ゆっくりね！
え あっ こうスか？
Go slowly.
Er, like this?
僕は 自転しながら 地球の
周りを 公転するから！
I'll rotate, while I orbit the Earth.
In an elliptical orbit!
だえんきどう
楕円軌道で！
《何 この遊び…》
What kind of game is this?
《もうちょっと 吾妻さんと
うまく話せたらいいのにな｡➡
I hope I'll get the chance to talk to Azuma some more...
仲良くなれたら スゲーいい｡
あだ名とか➡
I want to become friends with him.
Maybe we'd get closer if I gave him a nickname.
つけてあげたら
打ち解けるだろうか》
《アズアズ…》
Like Azu-Azu.
《ダメだ…殺される
やめとけ》
That won't work...
He'd kill me.
Forget it.
いくよ～ お父さん！
Here it comes, Dad.
吾妻さんって 甲子園に
行ったんですよね？確か｡
I heard that Azuma made it to the high school championships.
Yes, he was a catcher.
ええ キャッチャーでした｡
すごく厳しい部活だったんですよ➡
His team was very strict.
その後 防衛大学校を
卒業してからも 厳しい➡
After graduating from the National Defense Academy of Japan, he trained hard as a pilot.
パイロットの訓練を受けて 航空
自衛隊でも様々な訓練をして➡
And then he trained more with the Japan Air Self-Defense Force.
それで今は 月に行く訓練してるん
だから おかしいですよね｡
And now, he's training to go to the moon.
Isn't it funny?
彼は自分を 常に鍛えてないと
ダメみたいです｡
Apparently, he needs to keep training himself.
《スッゲーな…》
That's incredible.
それだけ厳しい訓練を
乗り越えてきた人だから➡
So I guess that presence he has comes from all the training he's survived.
あの貫禄なんですね｡
怖いものナシって感じだ｡
Nothing scares him.
そうでもないですよ｡
That's not true.
周りの変化には
対処しきれなかったみたいで｡
He wasn't able to adapt to the environment around him.
周りの変化？
The environment around him?
走り出したとたんに ぐっすりね｡
They fell asleep as soon as we left.
(吾妻)さっきは 何を
話してたんだ？南波と｡
So...
What were you talking to Nanba about?
We talked about your past.
興味深そうに聞いてたわ｡
He was very interested.
なんで俺にかまうんだ
あの兄弟は｡
Why do those brothers turn to me?
それは あなたがﾌﾞﾗｲｱﾝ･ｼﾞｪｲに
憧れてたのと同じじゃない？
Perhaps for the same reason you were drawn to Brian Jay?
≪おかえりなさい 吾妻さん！≫
Welcome back, Azuma.
Welcome back.
≪おかえりなさい！≫
Azuma, could you give us a smile?
≪吾妻さん すみません
もう少し笑顔で≫
≪少しカタイですね≫
≪そう そんな感じで≫
You're a little stiff.
Yes, like that.
え～ 日本人初の
月周回軌道 到達という事で｡
After becoming the first Japanese person to orbit the moon...
They're making this much of a fuss because I orbited the moon?
《月を周っただけで
こんなに騒がれるのか…》
Did you ever feel lonely when you were all alone out there in space?
≪地球から遠い 宇宙空間に
１人残されて➡
こどく
孤独感に
襲われませんでしたか？≫
《また その質問か…》
It's that question again.
いえ 孤独感はありませんでした
こうようかん
あったのは高揚感です｡
No.
I did not feel lonely.
I felt exhilarated.
(記者の声)⦅次は月面歩行ですね
吾妻さん⦆
Next, you'll be walking on the moon.
(記者の声)⦅日本の歴史に
名前が残りますよ！⦆
Your name will go down in Japanese history.
(記者の声)⦅日本人初の月面
たきお
歩行者 吾妻滝生！⦆
The first Japanese person on the moon, Azuma Takio.
(記者の声)⦅英雄ですよ～！⦆
You're a hero!
《余計な称号だ》
Just titles I don't need.
あ すみません 吾妻さん
また別の ご親戚の方から➡
Oh, excuse me, Azuma...
Another relative sent a message.
連絡がありまして
話したいと…｡
Can you talk?
どこの親戚ですか？
Who is it?
Uh...
え～と…お父さんのお兄さんの
奥さんの弟さん？
Your father's older brother's wife's younger brother?
わかりました
電話しておきます｡
Understood.
I'll call.
(担当者)すいません｡
Thank you.
《会ったこともない…》
I've never met him before.
≪吾妻さん！≫
吾妻さん！➡
Azuma!
Azuma, did you really turn down every endorsement deal?
ＣＭの依頼を 全部断ると
いうのは ほんとですか？
≪講演の依頼まで 断ったのは
何故ですか？➡
Why did you refuse to speak publicly?
Everyone wants to hear about the moon.
みんな 月の話を
聞きたがってますよ！≫
月での孤独感が
原因ですか？吾妻さん！
Was it due to the solitude you experienced at the moon,
Azuma?
失礼｡
≪あ～ 吾妻さん！≫
Excuse me.
A-Azuma?
(吾妻)《俺が 月で孤独だったと
言ってほしいのか？➡
Do they
want me to say that I was lonely orbiting the moon?
船内には 家族の声も
映像も届いていた｡➡
I could hear and see my family.
月に降りた２人のクルーも 時折
無線で冗談を言ってくれた｡➡
The two crew members on the moon would tell me jokes.
これだけ人が大勢いても わかって
くれる奴が１人もいないなら…》
If none of the people in this crowd understand that,
then I consider my current position
(吾妻)《今のほうが…孤独だ》
more lonely.
では 不安は
ありませんでしたか？
Were you ever worried?
W-Well...
それは まあ…｡
(吾妻)《家族にまで
マイクを向けるな！》
Don't point your microphones at my family!
ちょっと吾妻さん！
あなた！
Ah, wait, Azuma!
Dear!
現在
《一番わかってくれたのは
家族と…ブライアン》
The only ones who understood me were my family...
And Brian.
(ﾌﾞﾗｲｱﾝ)⦅パワフルな働きっぷり
とは 裏腹に➡
You're a powerful worker.
せんさい
お前は とても繊細な男だ
アズマ｡➡
But you're delicate on the inside, Azuma.
日本の歴史に名が残るとか 日本の
評価を決める重大な役割とかさ➡
When you feel the pressure of making your mark in Japanese history and bolstering your country's reputation,
you're not able to enjoy space anymore.
そんな重圧 気になって 宇宙で
楽しめねえだろ？お前⦆
そんなもんまで 背負う
必要はねえぞ アズマ⦆
This isn't your burden to bear, Azuma.
⦅なっ！➡
Right?
俺に任せろ！日本人初となる
ムーンウォーカーには➡
Let me handle this.
I'll recommend that Hibito become the first Japanese moon walker.
すいせん
ヒビトを推薦しておく｡あいつは
地上にいる時でも まるで➡
He's still on Earth, and his soul is already in zero gravity.
ハートはゼロＧみたいな奴だ｡
プカプカ フワフワと➡
He floats around without any pressure on him.
せお
重圧なんてものは背負わず…
そこら辺に➡
Like a cloud in the sky...
ポンと浮かべてやがるんだ⦆
(吾妻)《日々人 俺もブライアンの
言う通りだと思ってるよ》
Hibito, I agree with Brian.
Your first step
(吾妻)《お前なら きっと
誰よりも…》
(吾妻)《最初の一歩は
軽やかだろう》
will be lighter than anyone else's.
My right hand spent its days afraid of losing something
but wished to be held by my left hand
I lead you by the hand
Is my hand only there to hold my own hand now?
I can't lose it
Amidst my nagging disappointment that I can do nothing
I felt I wanted to do something
I let go again
I'm not alone in this world
If my hands can only hold two things
then I hope one of them is you
Not alone, not alone
I want our hearts to be connected
I want to be connected
Next time, on
Space Brothers
#33 Moon Rabbit
＜ずっと
知りたかったことがある＞
There's something I've always wanted to know.
＜私は 日々人の月面着陸を
どんな顔して見るのだろうか＞
How will I react when I see Hibito land on the moon?
＜ついに 私は
その答えを知ることになる…➡
I'm finally going to find out... But what?
…のは いいんだけど え～!?➡
Hibito?
日々人君 月面で
そんなことしちゃうの？＞
You're really going to do that on the moon?!
＜カラダ軽りぃ！＞
I feel so light!
When Hibito lands on the moon, he starts two new fads.
＜日々人は 月面着陸とともに
２つのブームを巻き起こす＞
Next time, on Space Brothers:
"Moon Rabbit"
Yeah, this totally sucks...
＜あ～やっぱり…最悪だ＞
パンパカパーン！
This Week's Space Photo
We've been awaiting the Dragon and its cargo.
What's inside...?
This week's space photo!
今週の宇宙写真です｡
すっげえ！
Awesome!